

Sridatri Dutta

MANAGER - SALES / SALES STRATEGY

- 7053143227 / 9090009740
- **♀** Gurgaon / India
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/sridatridutta/

ABOUT ME

Domain

Sales /Strategy & Ops -

- National A/C Manager (B2B Sales 1.4 yr.)
- TSM YLP (Telecom Sales Prepaid **2 yrs**.)

Marketing -

• Campaign Manager (Telecom – 5 mon.)

Sales Operations-

• Sales Intern (Handets – 6 mon.)

Information Technology-

• Software Developer (Java, SQL- 2 yrs.)

An alumnus of IMT- Ghaziabad with 5+ years of experience. Recently, worked with OYO as a National Accounts Manager, responsible for growing regional accounts at a National Scale which involved both acquisition and extraction. Prior to OYO, I was in Field Sales as a Management Trainee (as part of Young Leader's Program) with Idea Cellular in Prepaid Segment. Handled multiple projects to improve current and develop new processes.

SKILLS

8 / 10

Sales – B₂B, Retail

8 / 10

Account Management

9 / 10

BI & Analytics - Data Interpretation

7 / 10

Project Management

7/10

Campaign Management

8/10

Stake Holder Management

EXPERIENCE

NATIONAL ACCOUNT MANAGER - B2B SALES

Oyo Hotels and Homes Pvt. Ltd / Gurgaon / Sep'18 – Jan'20

Team Management | Account Management (Farming) | Client Acquisition (Hunting) | Collection

Sales | Account Management

1. Sep 2018 - Jan 2019:

Competition Portfolio: Built a revenue of 3Cr. (Sep'19) from 83L (Sep'18) by **strategic acquisition** and sustainable extraction. Majorly involved in acquiring new clients to increase OYO's market share.

2. Jan 2019 - Jan 2020:

Top Accounts Portfolio: Responsible for revenue delivery and growth of Top 100 Accounts of a portfolio of 15 Cr+ on a National Scale (Sep'19 onwards) by developing Account Development Plan and Customer Lifecycle Metric along with a team of 3. Focused towards increasing account extraction through various levers (credit, schemes, contests) along with improving collection efficiency.

- 3. Collaborating with the ground team for client visits to maximize profit by up-selling or cross-selling via tailoring products and schemes, resolving escalations and taking a central call over decisions made
- 4. **Demand Shaping** Incentive Planning, Demand Diversion to corporate specific portfolio properties resulting in positive Guest Experience (GX) and strengthening customer loyalty
- Competition Analysis Develop profiles of major competitors, including trended performance, strategies, identify threats and opportunities

EDUCATION

PGDM / Sales and Marketing

Institute of Management Technology, Ghaziabad 2014 - 2016

B. TECH / Computer Science Engineering

Amity School of Engineering and Technology 2008 - 2012

CERTIFICATION / SIX SIGMA GREEN BELT

British Standard Institution 2009 - 2010

Campus Finalist – Mahindra War Room

Agribusiness Sector – Business Plan for launch of branded fruits (2015)

Additional Projects Handled | Sales Operations

- 1. Drive, engage and interface with cross functional teams for the critical project rollout— **Demerger Launch to Corporate Clients,** collaborating with Legal, Finance, Product Teams ensuring smoother transition
- 2. Drive **Profitability** and Bottom Line P&L for Sales team by driving collection efficiency projects Provision Recovery in lieu with Sales and Finance teams, ensuring business continuity through smooth credit lines
- 3. Formulation of the company's Bill to Company policy to B2B clients to mitigate risk of revenue loss
- Formulating BTC (Bill to Company) contracts basis business generated, client engagement and credit references to set credit limits and ensure credit worthiness before passing on to Finance team and Legal Teams
- Strategize and improve processes to reduce credit exposure, resolve internal issues related to delay in payments from clients
- 6. Monitor pay-outs and commissions for all accounts based on business and credit hygiene
- 7. Optimize Guest Experience Operations by inter-process alignment with B2B Helpdesk for Top 100 clients

May'18 – Aug'18

Jul'16 – May'18

Apr'15 – Aug'15

CAMPAIGN MANAGER - MARKETING

Idea Cellular Ltd / Mumbai

- 1. Design & drive campaigns focused on customer engagement, churn reduction and loyalty framework to maximize revenue thus effectively managing customer life cycle
- 2. Creating and optimizing revenue-oriented campaigns using segmentation of target market and offering these segments respective prepaid voice & data products
- 3. Managing campaigns by analyzing over 150 customer KPIs through advanced analytics and supportive tools for a subscriber base of around 14 million customers
- 4. Ensuring customer retention by creating repeat campaigns and using predictive churn models
- 5. Conducting frequent market visits to interact with retailers and other stakeholders to understand consumer needs
- 6. Customer acquisition through lucrative product offerings and ensuring customer remains on network by analyzing customer usage behavior and share of wallet
- Creating and implementing a communication plan of products through different channels like SMS, OBD, website, My Idea app, push notifications and managing vendor teams/third party agencies for the effectiveness of promotion

Tools Used: SAS Customer Intelligence Studio, IMAGINE, SAS Campaign Manager

TERRITORY SALES MANAGER – PREPAID SALES (Young Leader)

Idea Cellular Ltd / Bangalore

Sales

- 1. Grew territory at an average of 35% month on month in SOGA, ranking consistently 2nd in Bangalore Zone
- 2. Awarded **Selling Star** award for the month of July for achieving 82% growth in Gross Activation and 44% growth in MNP. Ranked 4th among 309 Territory Sales Manager in Karnataka Circle
- 3. Managed 3 Distributors and an avg. of 4 Sales Executive per distributor with a revenue ranging from 35L 48L from Sim Card, Recharges and Data Sales
- 4. Gather market insights from competitors to help reduce churn
- 5. Plan BTL activities to increase brand recall among retailers and customers
- 6. Engaged field forces into Direct Selling Activities basis regular Market Analysis to identify high footfall areas, labor camps, bus stands, weekday markets
- 7. Engage teams in Cold Calling for SIM upgradation from 2G to 4G to increase data penetration in market
- 8. Increase profitability of Distributor and Sales Executives
- 9. Developing alternate channel support such as PDSA, HISP and DAP to drive growth in a challenging market
- 10. Driving essential business KPIs such as customer acquisition, customer market share, VLR quality, CMS, SOGA, MNP and data penetration
- 11. Motivational Speaker for empowering Women into Field Sales a platform provided through initiatives taken by HR

INTERN – SALES (Best Intern / Pre-Placement Offer)

Lava International / Noida

Sales Operation:

- 1. Design and pilot the Beat Plan Automation System for LAVA Sales Executives
- 2. Analysing and restructuring work ways of Territory Manager
- 3. Analysing the financial strength of a competitor brand based on primary and secondary researches
- 4. Hygiene audit Tracing illegally sold devices in the Sales Channel